archello.com 2012-06-11

# Privacy Statement

**Archello Privacy Policy**

**1\. Introduction**

Archello respects and protects the privacy of all users of our Website. Archello makes every reasonable effort to ensure that all personal information provided to Archello will at all times be handled confidentially and will be used solely for the objectives as specified in this Privacy Policy. The processing of personal data therefore occurs in accordance with the applicable laws and regulations in the field of privacy. This Privacy Policy is intended to inform you of the Archello policy with regard to the collection and use of personal data. By visiting the Archello website located at [www.archello.com](http://www.archello.com/ "www.archello.com"), you are accepting the practices outlined in this Privacy Policy. 

If you are under the age of 16, please do not attempt to register for Archello or provide any personal information about yourself to us. If we learn that we have collected personal information from a person under the age of 16, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from a person under the age of 16, please contact us. 

Unless stated otherwise, our current privacy policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account. You should review this Privacy Policy periodically to review any changes. 

**2\. Information We Receive**

Information you provide to us: 

**Information About Yourself.** When you sign up for Archello you provide us with your name, email, gender, and birth date. You will also be able to add a picture of yourself. In some cases we may ask for additional information for security reasons or to provide specific services to you. Once you register you can provide other information about yourself by connecting with, for example, the company you work for, materials, products, projects, and people. You can also provide personal information about yourself, such as your interests and expertise. 

**Information About your Company.** When you sign up for Archello, if not already done so, you can register your companies name, its website, and address. There is the possibility to provide more information about your company for example telephone and fax. If making the company you can make yourself an administrator for your company. 

**Content.** One of the primary reasons people use Archello is to share stories. This could be a story on a project, material or product. Archello also allows users to follow projects, materials and products. You can add stories as a company or as yourself. When adding a story you can provide photographs, video, text and other media formats. These stories can be commented on by other users and stories added to the project alongside your story. 

**Follower Information.** We offer contact importer tools to help you upload your connections’ addresses so that you can find your connections’ on Archello, and invite your contacts who do not have Archello accounts to join. If you do not want us to store this information, please contact us. 

Information we collect when you interact with Archello: 

**Site activity information.** We keep track of some of the actions you take on Archello, such as adding connections (including joining a group or connecting to a project), creating a story or commenting on a product. In some cases you are also taking an action when you provide information or content to us. For example, if you share a video, in addition to storing the actual content you uploaded, we might log the fact that you shared it. 

**Access Device and Browser Information.** When you access Archello from a computer, mobile phone, or other device, we may collect information from that device about your browser type, location, and IP address, as well as the pages you visit. 

**Cookie Information.** We use "cookies" (small pieces of data we store for an extended period of time on your computer, mobile phone, or other device) to make Archello easier to use, to make our advertising better, and to protect both you and Archello. For example, we use them to store your login ID (but never your password) to make it easier for you to login whenever you come back to Archello. We also use them to confirm that you are logged into Archello, and to know when you are interacting with Archello applications and websites, and our advertisements. You can remove or block cookies using the settings in your browser, but in some cases that may impact your ability to use Archello. 

Information we receive from third parties: 

**Information from other websites.** We may institute programs with advertising partners and other websites in which they share information with us: 

We may ask advertisers to tell us how our users responded to the ads we showed them (and for comparison purposes, how other users who didn’t see the ads acted on their site). This data sharing, commonly known as “conversion tracking,” helps us measure our advertising effectiveness and improve the quality of the advertisements you see. 

We may receive information about whether or not you’ve seen or interacted with certain ads on other sites in order to measure the effectiveness of those ads. 

If in any of these cases we receive data that we do not already have, we will “anonymize” it within 180 days, meaning we will stop associating the information with any particular user. If we institute these programs, we will only use the information in the ways we explain in the “How We Use Your Information” section below. 

**Information from other users.** We may collect information about you from other Archello users, such as when a user connects you to a project, product, material or indicates a connection to you. 

**3\. Sharing information on Archello.**

**Name and Profile Picture.** Archello is designed to make it easy for you to find and connect with others. For this reason, your name, location and profile picture are displayed. If you are uncomfortable with sharing your profile picture, you should delete it (or not add one). This is the same for companies which you are an administrator for. 

**Contact Information.** Your contact information settings are controlled by ‘My Privacy Settings’ tab under the person tab and ‘Settings’ tab under the company tab. Here you can choose 3 levels of contact privacy: 

Show contact information to everybody

Show contact information only to ‘My Connections’ 

Don’t show my contact information 

Don’t show me at all 

**Personal Information.** Your personal information like expertise and interests will be viewable by every user on Archello if you choose to add this information. To add this information is your choice. 

**Connections.** Archello enables you to connect with virtually anything you want, from your company, products, materials and projects. If you wish to disconnect with something you can do this on ‘my connections’ tab and clicking ‘disconnect’. 

**Followers.** Archello enables you to follow virtually anything you want, this allows you to keep track of certain projects, products, materials etc. People can also follow you and your company. If you wish to stop someone following you or your company you may click ‘block’ on the ‘my profile’ tab from your list of ‘followers’. If you wish to stop following people, companies, projects etc. you may click ‘remove following’ on the ‘my profile’tab from your list ‘following’. The same applies to companies which you are an administrator for. 

**Gender and Birth Date.** In addition to name and email address, we require you to provide your gender and birth date during the registration process. We ask for your date of birth to verify that you are 16 or older, and so that we can better limit your access to content and advertisements that are not age appropriate. If you do not want other users to know your gender or birth date do not add them. 

**Other.** Here are some other things to remember: 

Some of the content you share and the actions you take will show up on the home page. 

If another user connects you to a project, you can remove the tag. Even after you remove information from your profile or delete your account, copies of that information may remain viewable elsewhere to the extent it has been shared with others, it was otherwise distributed pursuant to your ‘My Privacy Settings’, or it was copied or stored by other users. 

You understand that information might be reshared or copied by other users. 

Certain types of communications that you send to other users cannot be removed, such as messages. 

If you use an external source to publish information to Archello (such as a mobile application or a Connect site), you should check the privacy setting for that post, as it is set by that external source. 

**4\. Information You Share With Third Parties.**

**Exporting Information.** You (and those you make your information available to) may use tools like RSS feeds, mobile phone address book applications, or copy and paste functions, to capture, export (and in some cases, import) information from Archello, including your information and information about you. For example, if you share your phone number with your friends, they may use third party applications to sync that information with the address book on their mobile phone. 

**Advertisements.** Sometimes the advertisers who present ads on Archello use technological methods to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalise advertising content. 

**Links.** When you click on links on Archello you may leave our site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites, and we encourage you to read their privacy statements. 

**5\. How We Use Your Information**

We use the information we collect to try to provide a safe, efficient, and customised experience. Here are some of the details on how we do that: 

**To manage the service.** We use the information we collect to provide our services and features to you, to measure and improve those services and features, and to provide you with customer support. We use the information to prevent potentially illegal activities. We also use a variety of technological systems to detect and address anomalous activity and screen content to prevent abuse such as spam. These efforts may on occasion result in a temporary or permanent suspension or termination of some functions for some users. 

**To contact you.** We may email you with essential service-related announcements from time to time. 

**Newsletter.** We give you the option to receive Archello newsletters from time to time. You may subscribe and unsubscribe on your ‘my settings’ tab. You may also unsubscribe by link in each newsletter. 

**To serve personalized advertising to you.** We don’t share your information with advertisers without your consent. We allow advertisers to choose the characteristics of users who will see their advertisements and we may use any of the non-personally identifiable attributes we have collected (including information you may have decided not to show to other users, such as your location or other sensitive personal information or preferences) to select the appropriate audience for those advertisements. For example, we might use your interest in wood buildings to show you ads for wood materials, but we do not tell the wood material company who you are. Even though we do not share your information with advertisers without your consent, when you click on or otherwise interact with an advertisement there is a possibility that the advertiser may place a cookie in your browser and note that it meets the criteria they selected. 

**To supplement your profile.** We may use information about you that we collect from other Archello users, projects and stories to supplement your profile (such as when you connect to a project). In such cases we generally give you the ability to remove the content (such as allowing you to remove your connection to a project). 

**To make suggestions.** We use your profile information, the addresses you import through our contact importers, and other relevant information, to help you connect with associates, stories, projects, materials and products including making suggestions to you and other users that you connect with on Archello. For example, if another user imports the same project as you do, we may suggest that you connect with each other. 

**Memorializing Accounts.** We may close an account if we find out a user has become deceased. An account will be closed if we receive a formal request from the users next of kin or other proper legal request to do so. 

**6\. How We Share Information**

Archello is about sharing information with others, friends, associates, companies and people in your communities. Everything you share on Archello will be available for users to view. We share your information with third parties when we believe the sharing is permitted by you, reasonably necessary to offer our services, or when legally required to do so. For example: 

**When you invite a connection to join**. When you ask us to invite a connection to join Archello, we will send your connection a message on your behalf using your name. The invitation may also contain information about other users your connection might know. We may also send up to two reminders to them in your name. 

**When you choose to share your information with marketers.** You may choose to share information with marketers or electronic commerce providers that are not associated with Archello through on-site offers. This is entirely at your discretion and we will not provide your information to these marketers without your consent. 

**To help your friends find you.** By default, we make certain information you have posted to your profile available in search results on Archello to help your connections find you. However, you can control who can see some of this information, as well as who can find you in searches, through your ‘my settings’ tab. We also partner with email and instant messaging providers to help their users identify which of their contacts are Archello users, so that we can promote Archello to those users. 

**To help improve or promote our service.** Sometimes we share aggregated information with third parties to help improve or promote our service. But we only do so in such a way that no individual user can be identified or linked to any specific action or information. 

**To provide you with services.** We may provide information to service providers that help us bring you the services we offer. For example, we may use third parties to help host our website, send out email updates about Archello, remove repetitive information from our user lists, process payments, or provide search results or links (including sponsored links). These service providers may have access to your personal information for use for a limited time, but when this occurs we implement reasonable contractual and technical protections to limit their use of that information to helping us provide the service. 

**To advertise our services.** We may ask advertisers outside of Archello to display ads promoting our services. We may ask them to deliver those ads based on the presence of a cookie. We may use Archello’s content which includes persons, companies, stories, products and materials to promote the site. 

**To offer joint services.** We may provide services jointly with other companies. If you use these services, we may share your information to facilitate that service. However, we will identify the partner and present the joint service provider’s privacy policy to you before you use that service. 

**To respond to legal requests and prevent harm.** We may disclose information pursuant to subpoenas, court orders, or other requests (including criminal and civil matters) if we have a good faith belief that the response is required by law. This may include respecting requests from jurisdictions outside of the Netherlands where we have a good faith belief that the response is required by law under the local laws in that jurisdiction, apply to users from that jurisdiction, and are consistent with generally accepted international standards. We may also share information when we have a good faith belief it is necessary to prevent fraud or other illegal activity, to prevent imminent bodily harm, or to protect ourselves and you from people violating our Terms Of Use. This may include sharing information with other companies, lawyers, courts or other government entities. 

**Transfer in the Event of Sale or Change of Control.** If the ownership of all or substantially all of our business changes, we may transfer your information to the new owner so that the service can continue to operate. In such a case, your information would remain subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Policy. 

**7\. How You Can Change or Remove Information**

**Editing your profile.** You may change or remove your personal or company profile information at any time by going to youre ‘my profile’ page and clicking ‘Edit’ Information will be updated immediately. 

**Deleting your profile.** If you want to stop using your account you may delete it. When you delete an account, it is permanently deleted from Archello. You should only delete your account if you are certain you never want to reactivate it. You may delete your account on your ‘my settings’ tab. 

**Limitations on removal.** Even after you remove information from your profile or delete your account, copies of that information may remain viewable elsewhere to the extent it has been shared with others, it was otherwise distributed pursuant to your ‘my privacy settings’, or it was copied or stored by other users. However, your name will no longer be associated with that information on Archello. We may retain certain information to prevent identity theft and other misconduct even if deletion has been requested. If you have given third party applications or websites access to your information, they may retain your information to the extent permitted under their terms of service or privacy policies. But they will no longer be able to access the information through Archello after you disconnect from them. 

**Backup copies.** Removed and deleted information may persist in backup copies for up to 90 days, but will not be available to others. 

**8\. How We Protect Information**

We do our best to keep your information secure, but we need your help. 

**Steps we take to keep your information secure.** We keep your account information on a secured server behind a firewall. When you enter sensitive information (such as passwords), we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We also use automated and social measures to enhance security, such as analyzing account behavior for fraudulent or otherwise anomalous behavior, may limit use of site features in response to possible signs of abuse, may remove inappropriate content or links to illegal content, and may suspend or disable accounts for violations of our Terms of Use. 

**Risks inherent in sharing information.** Although we allow you to set privacy options that limit access to your information, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We cannot control the actions of other users with whom you share your information. We cannot guarantee that only authorized persons will view your information. We cannot ensure that information you share on Archello will not become publicly available. We are not responsible for third party circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures on Archello. You can reduce these risks by using common sense security practices such as choosing a strong password, using different passwords for different services, and using up to date antivirus software.

Report Violations. You should report any security violations by contacting us. 

**9\. Contact Us**

Archello welcomes concerns and feedbacks with regards to this privacy policy or anything to do with the site. If you have any questions, concerns, suggestions or comments about our privacy policy, contact our support team by email ([support@archello.com](mailto:support@archello.com)), by post: Binnenhof 62D, 1412 LC, Naarden, The Netherlands, by telephone (035) 69 20 874 or by fax (035) 69 22 678. 

Date of last revision: 22nd of June 2010
